<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>http://govidat.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:04:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://govidat.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain basics - Merkle tree</title>
      <link>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics-merkle-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:04:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics-merkle-tree/</guid>
      <description>All the transactions that ever happened in a bitcoin are stored in the distributed database.
- Does it mean that a participant has to manage a very large database? - Does it mean that to verify if a transaction is valid, one has to process all the data from the very beginning?
Answer lies in Merkle tree and this article is to touch on few basics.
Merkle tree In cryptography and computer science, a hash tree or Merkle tree is a tree in which every non-leaf node is labelled with the hash of the labels or values (in case of leaves) of its child nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain basics - cryptography</title>
      <link>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 10:16:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Source: Bitcoin paper
A blockchain database is immutable and is cryptographically protected.
This article is on few very basic aspects of cryptography.
SHA-256 SHA-2 (Secure Hash Algorithm) is a set of cryptographic hash functions designed by United States NSA.
Key aspects of a hash function are :
 It is a one way function. From a known output value one cannot derive the input value.
 It mathematically converts the input to a standard sized output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain basics</title>
      <link>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:05:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-basics/</guid>
      <description>This article is to simplify blockchain to business users.
Blockchain is an innovative way of combining the plus points of a few available technologies to meet some inherent business requirements. At its core, it uses a)distributed database and b) immutable database.
Distributed database means that the same database is shared with many users and each have a copy of the same in their systems. This is not a new concept and there are many different uses for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 12:49:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://govidat.github.io/blog/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog I will try to relate my learnings in technology to the business requirements around me. It is an exciting time and there are so many technological developments in recent times. Actually too many and too difficult to keep up with them. At the same time, I am trying to relate these with the business requirements and see differentiate the useful from just cool stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>